<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 14:39:59 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>test</title>
      <link>http://example.org/article/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 14:39:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/article/test/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Read Off to Be the Wizard (Magic 2.0 Book 1)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/off-to-be-the-wizard-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 14:39:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/off-to-be-the-wizard-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This covers chapter 1 through&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scott Meyer&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Off to Be the Wizard&lt;/em&gt; is a science fiction book whose protagonist, Martin Banks, ends up discovering a computer file that contains information describing the world. He also discovers that changing the file changes reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin considers the existentially terrifying implications of the file for a few minutes, then moves on to goofing around with his newfound power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should note that I&amp;rsquo;ve read this book once before, so this Let&amp;rsquo;s Read will be my first reread of the book. That should be a sufficiently confusing clarification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we&amp;rsquo;re living under a new authoritarian regime, let&amp;rsquo;s start at the very beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martin Banks enjoyed science. As a child he read about people who made huge, world&amp;ndash;changing discoveries, and he had wondered what emotions he would feel if he ever discovered something really earth&amp;ndash;shattering. Now he had made just such a discovery, and he was surprised to find that the answer was absolute bowel&amp;ndash;loosening terror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the opening paragraph of the book, and it&amp;rsquo;s an interesting one. Martin has made an earth&amp;ndash;shattering discovery and is terrified by it. He&amp;rsquo;s not having as fun of a discovery as Archimedes, who apocryphally ran naked through the streets of Syracuse (Sicily, not New York) after discovering a way to measure the volume of irregular objects as he was taking a bath. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty simple inference that this discovery was something that upset Martin&amp;rsquo;s worldview, rather than an easy way to determine if a golden crown had had some of its volume replaced with silver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight, Martin is alone in his apartment, an ordinary night judging by the TV on in the background to provide &amp;ldquo;the illusion of human contact&amp;rdquo;. And on this ordinary night he&amp;rsquo;s doing what he always does &amp;mdash; poking around the servers of a company he&amp;rsquo;s hacked into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Martin] knew that many of the things he was doing were technically illegal, but he kept his tampering strictly harmless. That way ,the authorities wouldn&amp;rsquo;t bother with him as long as more destructive perpetrators were roaming free. [Martin] told himself that, but he was too smart to really believe it or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a variation on the theme of Martin not wanting to believe things that are inconvenient, or to change his ppbehavior &amp;mdash; even if he knows that what he&amp;rsquo;s doing is wrong or bad for him in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After hacking into the servers of a cell phone company, Martin finds what strikes him as a suspiciously boringly named file. He pokes around in the file and notices that the values inside of it are constantly changing, which is the first hint that something about this file is odd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, Martin searches the file for his name. Unless Martin&amp;rsquo;s being compelled by the plot, this is a pretty strong indication that he&amp;rsquo;s self&amp;ndash;absorbed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem egocentric, but Martin wasn&amp;rsquo;t worried about that. He had spent a lot of time thinking about himself, and had come to the conclusion that he was definitely not self&amp;ndash;absorbed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, that checks out then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some poking around in the file, Martin discovers that by editing values in the file, the things they represent in the real world are changed. He changes his own height to 6&amp;rsquo;2&amp;rdquo;, then 6&amp;rsquo;1&amp;rdquo;, then back to 5&amp;rsquo;11&amp;rdquo;. After this, he closes the file, goes to bed, and has a quiet crisis about the world he lives in being a computer simulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After six hours of forced introspection, Martin turns to a dose of bourbon and sleeping pills to drift off to unconsciousness at the end of chapter one. That seems like a dangerous decision to make, but it&amp;rsquo;s possible that discovering that saying you exist has just changed from being an obvious fact to a contentious philosophical position makes you less concerned about the consequences of mixing depressants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chapter Two&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After zombieing his way through work, Martin comes home determined to never look at the file again. Like most good intentions, this one is immediately rationalized away, and Martin decides that he needs to understand the file first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His attempts to reason with the file run uncover some problems with his course of action. Specifically, none of the values in the file are labeled. His height, obviously, is something we&amp;rsquo;d recognize &amp;mdash; luckily it was in imperial units rather than metric &amp;mdash; but other stats could represent his intelligence, vision, number of heart beats remaining so discretion is probably the best part of valor here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He finds his bank balance, which he can be sure is correct, and shifts the decimal point one place to the right giving himself a balance of $835.00. This chapter we&amp;rsquo;ve already had some important information about Martin provided to us. One: his day job is not as a programmer, as you would conceivably believe from his hobbies. Shuffling paperwork and having a bank balance of $83.50 are not things that are typically associated with programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there are two parts to any theft: taking a thing away from its owner, and keeping it for yourself. Martin wasn’t taking anything from anybody, so he figured it wasn’t theft, or at least that he was fifty percent less likely to get caught. It was flimsy reasoning, but it was good enough to let him sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More rationalizations from Martin, along with a lot of assumptions about how the law works. This is a book, so something has to go wrong for the main character and it&amp;rsquo;s a safe bet that Martin&amp;rsquo;s going to end up in trouble because of his assumptions and general laziness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chapter ends with Martin returning his bank balance to normal, mixing more bourbon and sleeping pills, sleepwalking through his next day of work, and thinking of all the things he shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use the file to do. It seems like our Martin is maturing and becoming responsible when faced with the reality of his newfound power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having spent all Friday collecting dangerous ideas, that night when he sat at his computer, he had no shortage of things to try, and a whole weekend to try them in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevermind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re two chapters into the book now, and I think we&amp;rsquo;re starting to get a pretty good handle on Martin as a person. He&amp;rsquo;s smart, but seemingly low on willpower, gumption, possibly stick-to-it-iveness. At the very least he has the skills for a  job that would leave him with a checking account balance that&amp;rsquo;s at least in the triple digits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are convincing arguments to be made that money and creature comforts aren&amp;rsquo;t everything, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think they apply here. If Martin was deliberately going without work for the sake of art, or out of some moral stance, or even if it let him pursue the lifestyle he wanted to outside of work, then that would neatly justify his lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact is, after what can be assumed was a period of time going with the flow, Martin is now stuck in a rut. He&amp;rsquo;s just doing the bare minimum to live at a relative level of comfort, and not doing anything to change that. He&amp;rsquo;s at rest, in stasis, or if we put our judgmental hat, he&amp;rsquo;s stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, was stuck. Finding the file is going to be the push that gets Martin out of his rut and into adventure &amp;mdash; which is a nice way of saying trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time we&amp;rsquo;ll see how much trouble Martin can get himself into before other people start helping him into more.
.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/OtBtW3to/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/OtBtW3to/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-3&#34;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fresh after deciding not to abuse the file, Martin finds himself with Friday night and the rest of the weekend to abuse the file in ways limited by only his imagination and (rarely) his instinct for self protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After creating an encrypted copy of the part of the file that describes himself, it&amp;rsquo;s time to adjust that bank account. Editing it for the third time in 24 hours, Martin increases it to $83,500.00, continuing his neat and orderly trend of only altering the value by powers of ten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to be careful, [Martin] thought. I don’t want to screw this up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, Martin does not listen to his own sage advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While poking around in the file, Martin makes some discoveries and reasonable assumptions. Granted, it may be reasonable to assume some things about how a file that can rewrite reality works, but less reasonable to make changes to that file based on what is necessarily guesswork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, thinking carefully about these things isn&amp;rsquo;t Martin&amp;rsquo;s strong suit. He looks for and finds his latitude and longitude and makes the intuited leap that his position is calculated relative to the earth rather than to something else, or absolutely. I realize determining your position absolutely in the universe is impossible, but Martin&amp;rsquo;s living in a computer simulation so that could conceivably be possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Martin&amp;rsquo;s guesswork only ends in mild disaster. He decides to fly and adds one foot to his altitude above sea level. After making that edit he falls to the ground from a height of one foot. With all the elan of a lifelong nerd, Martin falls hard on the ground and makes enough noise to disturb his downstairs neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More experiments follow and Martin falls (loudly, again) because he teleported while sitting down. After such continued success he decides that now is the time to teleport to the parking lot of a Boston Market exactly one mile a way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because he&amp;rsquo;s been burned before, Martin really plans this teleport out. He stands up, crouches for balance and teleports. One mile away, in the parking lot of a Boston Market, Martin appears without his phone, car, or keys. He walks that mile home without shoes as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at the apartment, he gets his spare key from the downstairs neighbor, and rather than apologizing for being loud, decides to gaslight her about not being home instead. Martin seems like a pretty great person so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The upsetting thing is that the author seems to be mostly on Martin&amp;rsquo;s side about lying to the neighbor. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s in service of hiding that he can teleport, but it feels mostly like Martin getting one over on his annoying neighbor by convincing her that some loud burglar was in his apartment. Seems like Martin didn&amp;rsquo;t think that particular strategy all the way through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Safely back at his apartment, Martin decides that his physical travel has gone so well that he should try time travel. He&amp;rsquo;s disappointed when his attempt to travel to the future doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. He consoles himself, literally, when a future version of himself appears and tells him to try traveling to the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin, after recovering from the shock of meeting himself and finding himself lacking in looks, travels to the past. Now the roles are reversed, and Martin gives himself the hint to travel to the past while being judged unattractive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin returns to his original time and resolves to be smoother the next time he meets himself. Just then, a future version of himself appears and invites him to play poker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin has a very particular sense of smooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like this time travel section a lot. It&amp;rsquo;s funny, it efficiently establishes how time travel works in this story (paradoxes? Never heard of em), and gives some nice character insight into Martin. Namely, that he&amp;rsquo;s not a very charitable person, even to himself (provided that he actually sees himself as a separate person).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chapter Four&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, Martin recollects his break even poker game while nursing a hangover. The hangover comes from him needing yet more bourbon and sleeping pills the stop carb down enough to rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He takes stock of his experiments with the file and realizes he needs to slow down and think through his plans before he seriously injures himself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>